我们是宝石战士
We are the Crystal Gems
本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
终日拯救世界
we'll always save the day
■
时间轴： 树叶
如果你感到怀疑
and if you think we can't
我们总能找到出路
we'll always find a way
■
翻译： Peace
所以全世界人们都信任
that's why the people of this world believe in...
■
校订： 树叶
石榴  紫晶
Garnet, Amethyst...
和珍珠
and Pearl...
还有史蒂文
and Steven!
宇宙小子  第二季第二集
Steven Universe  S02E02  Open Book
书中世界
■
后期： 树叶  小黑
所以  你觉得书的结局如何
So, what did you think of the ending?
呃  我觉得结局写在第917页
Uh... I thought it was on page 917.
我觉得这结局简直糟透了
I thought it was a disaster!
整本书似乎一直在铺垫
All the books leading up to this seemed to be taking on and
为了推翻那些魔法桥段
subverting these witch tropes ...
作为山寨作品真有自知之明  是吧
really self-aware about being a pastiche, you know?
但到了最后  所有这些都毫无用处
But in the end, none of that even mattered.
丽莎和她会说话的猎鹰领导起义军
Lisa and her talking falcon, rebels challenging the stifling
挑战传统魔法的官僚制度  我爱这个情节
traditions of the magical bureaucracy ... I loved that.
但然后她的猎鹰化为人形  他们喜结连理
Then her falcon turns into a human and they get married?!
这完全脱离了反独裁主义的核心
It completely dropped all the anti-authoritarian
甚至还用50页的篇幅描写她的结婚蛋糕
stuff and described her wedding cake for 50 pages!
说得对  那蛋糕最多就值20页
Yeah! That cake was worthy of 20 pages, tops!
-那上面连草莓都没有  -我猜一定是这本书火了之后
- There weren't even strawberries on it! - I bet since the books got so popular
出版商开始给作者施压
the publisher put pressure on the author
让他减弱结局的深度来迎合大众口味
to water down the end for a larger audience appeal.
与艺术创作不同  现实世界总是无法逃脱
Unlike art, the real world can't always win against
权力铁链的禁锢
the iron chains of authority.
总之这是我的观点
That's my theory, anyway.
这太令我失望了  毕竟我花了额外的钱
It's just disappointing, considering I invested extra money
来买这个附带地图的精装版
in the hardcover copies... with maps.
我真希望我能给你一个新的结局
I wish I could give you a new ending.
神庙之门  它为我开启了
The temple door ... it opened for me!
我能在里面创造任何我想要的东西
I can make anything I want in there!
我可以创造一个新的结局
I can make us a new ending!
真的吗  那咱们还等什么
Really? Well, what are we waiting for?!
真酷
Cool!
这里是我妈妈的房间  我能控制它  就像这样
This is my mom's room. I can control it, like this.
我想要一只小小的漂浮鲸鱼和我击掌
I want a tiny, floating whale to give me some fin.
不可思议  你是怎么做到的
Unbelievable! How does it work?
在这里可以用云来制作东西
The room can make stuff out of clouds.
-任何东西都可以做  -任何吗
- We can make anything. - Anything?
做第四卷里那个无限市场怎么样
How 'bout the infinity fair from book 4
有来自成千上万个不同国度的商人
with merchants from a million lands
贩卖的商品来自各个已经绝迹或还未成形的文明
selling goods from cultures long gone and yet to be?
还是简单点好  我们可不想让这间房超载
We should probably keep it simple. We don't want to overload the room.
只做一半的无限市场怎么样  不对  那样还是无限的
How 'bout half the infinity fair? Oh. That's still infinity.
简单  好吧  那最重要的
Simple. Okay. Well, what really matters
就是角色了  你应该变成阿基米克勒斯
are the characters. You should be Archimicarus.
好的  房间  我想变成一只猎鹰
Okay. Room, I want to be a falcon!
噢  对了
Oh, yeah.
必须越简单越好
Got to keep it simple.
太神奇了  现在轮到我
Amazing! Okay, my turn.
房间  我想变成丽莎
Room, I want to be Lisa.
我需要描述得更精确吗
Do I need to be more specific?
你说猎鹰的时候就很概括
You were pretty general with the falcon thing.
抱歉  我想这个房间只能
Oh, sorry. I guess the room only makes
做出我想要的东西  我们可能玩不成了
stuff when I want it. Maybe this won't work after all.
那你为什么不让它做出一间戏服店呢
Why don't you just have it make a costume shop?
对啊  好主意
Oh, yeah! Good idea!
我想要一间戏服店
I want a costume shop!
哇  这里什么都有  甚至还有她儿时的长袍
Wow! This place has everything ... even her childhood tunic!
等等  你以为那是红色的吗
Wait. You thought it was red?
对啊  落日的颜色
Yeah, the color of the setting sun!
矿山的夕阳是黑色的  史蒂文
The sun sets black over the mines, Steven.
你要扮成年轻的丽莎吗
Are you gonna be young Lisa?
如果我们真的要改编书里的内容  那我就准备
Well, if we're really reworking this thing, I'm gonna
用每本书里最好的装备  成为终极版的丽莎
make the ultimate Lisa with the best gear from every book.
比如  如果她的铁剑从没丢掉呢
Like, what if she never lost her iron sword?
还有斗篷和胸针
And the cloak and the clasp
-更是不可或缺的标志  -那当然
- are too signature not to do. - For sure!
还有我一直很喜欢第三部里火山那部分
And I always liked the dragon whisker boots from
-提到的龙须靴子  -你穿好了吗
- the volcano stuff in book 3. - Are you almost done?
-再等一下  -快出来吧
- Wait a minute! - Come out!
我想看看你
I want to see you!
-天啊  你看起来超棒  -谢谢
- Whoa! You look awesome! - Thanks!
好啦  我们开始吧
Okay. Let's do this.
在故事的最后  丽莎和她的猎鹰密友
So, at the end of the series, Lisa and her falcon familiar,
阿基米克勒斯  站在圣坛前
Archimicarus, are at the altar...
在牧师的见证下  准备结婚
with a cleric... about to get married.
但我们不想要这种结局  那么  取而代之的是
But we don't want that ending. So, instead ... hmm.
我也不知道  你怎么想
Uh... I-I don't know. What do you think?
-你是怎么想的  -那么
- Hmm. What do you think? - Uh... well...
来个不一样的求婚如何  丽莎
h-how 'bout a different proposal, Lisa ...
请求合作经商  我们来一起创业吧
a business proposal? We can start a business together
通过卖  火鸡腿赚钱
and sell ... sell... turkey legs to make money
-来帮助起义军同伴们  -对啊  这个主意好
- to help out our fellow rebel comrades! - Yeah, that's great!
如果可以的话  给我一把伞吧  房间
I want an umbrella with that, if you would, room.
火鸡腿  起义军的火鸡腿
Turkey legs! Get your rebel turkey legs!
火鸡腿  你觉得我作为一只猎鹰
Turkey legs! You think it's okay for me
-可以吃这些吗  -你是可是鸟中的猛禽
- to eat this if I'm a falcon? - You are a bird of prey.
那么作为商业伙伴
So, what should our next move be
我们接下来应该做什么呢  -你说呢
- as business partners? - You tell me.
我吗
Yeah？
我们来喂风蜥蜴吧
Let's feed the wind lizard.
快看他
Look at this guy!
-长得真反叛的样子  -哇  是第四卷里的内容
- He totally looks like a rebel! - Wow! From book 4!
我知道他住在山里
Now, I know he lives in the mountains,
但他听说了我们的火鸡腿
but he's just visiting because he heard about
就来这里拜访  丽莎
these turkey legs. Lisa
-你愿意尽地主之谊吗  -好的
- would you like to do the honors? - Okay.
-他把骨头都吃了  -真棒
- He ate the bones! - Okay!
我想我们的事业算是成功了
I guess our business is a success.
-你说是就是  -所以现在呢
- If you think so. - So, what now?
你不是说它应该有更多反独裁的内容嘛
Didn't you have a bunch of ideas that it needed to be more anti-authority and stuff?
那当然
Sure.
好吧
Okay.
那么我们  被政府所阻止
So... we're... we ... we're stopped by the authorities
因为  因为我们无照经营
because ... because we're selling without a permit
而且还没到驾驶小推车的法定年龄
and we're not old enough to drive a cart.
但这些是自由放养的火鸡  它们不会听从任何人
But these are, uh, free-range turkeys, and they didn't listen to anybody
我们也要这样做  不是吗
and that's what we're gonna do, right?!
-你怎么想都可以  -真的吗
- Whatever you think. - Really?
好吧  那我觉得他们
All right. And then I think they...
不喜欢  他们要攻击我们
don't like that... and they attack us.
你阻止不了我们
You can't stop us!
天哪  这些家伙真是腐败
Geez! These guys are corrupt.
-我们该怎么对付他们啊  -你觉得应该怎么办
- What should we do about 'em, huh? - What do you think we should do?
别这样  我已经很努力地在想啦
C-Come on! I'm really trying here!
你想要故事如何结束
How do you want the story to end?
我不知道  我做这一切都是为了你
I don't know. I just wanted to do this for you.
你都不像你了
This isn't really like you.
我不想让你
I ... I don't want you to just
按我的吩咐做事  -你想让我不要
- do what I want. - Uh... Uh... you want me to not
-做  你想做的事  -康妮  你还好吗
- d-do what you want? - Connie, are you all right?
我想要你想要的  想要的
I want what you want ... what
你想要  想要  想要
you want ... want ... want ... want ... want ... want ...
-想要  想要  想要  -我想要一只小小的
- want ... want... - I want a tiny
漂浮鲸鱼和我击掌
floating whale to give me some fin.
我想要一间戏服店
I want a costume shop!
我想看看你
I want to see you!
是我  是我创造了你
- I-I created you.
想要  想要  想要
... want ... want ... want...
你不是康妮  我一定是把真的康妮
You're not Connie! I must have left the real Connie
留在戏服店了  她现在可能在任何地方
back at the costume shop! Sh-She could be anywhere!
不不不  够了  我退出游戏
No, no, no, no, no! I'm done! I'm done playing!
你为什么没和其他东西一样消失
Why didn't you disappear with everything else?!
是你让我别按照你的吩咐做事
You told me not to do what you wanted.
-康妮在哪啊  -史蒂文
- Where is Connie?! - Steven!
-史蒂文  -康妮
- Steven! - Connie?
康妮  是你吗
C-Connie?! Is that you?!
请放我走吧
Please let me go.
-我想找到真的康妮  -是你让我不要
- I want to find the real Connie! - You told me you wanted ...
跟这个无关
It doesn't matter!
拜托别再跟着我了  我不想让你跟着我
Please don't follow me. I don't want you to follow me!
小推车
Cart!
风蜥蜴
Uh... Uh, wind lizard!
康妮  你能听见吗
Uh... Uh... Uh... Connie, can you hear me?!
史蒂文  史蒂文
Steven? Steven!
康妮  我这就来了
Connie! I'm almost there!
就差一点点
Just a little bit furthe...
求你了
Please!
我不想要你  我想要真的康妮
I don't want you! I want the real Connie!
我知道你内心想要什么
I know what you really want.
-我知道你的真实感受  -史蒂文
- I know how you really feel. - Steven?!
史蒂文  终于找到你了
Ah, Steven, finally! There you... are.
救命啊
Ugh! Ugh! Help!
离他远点
Keep away from him!
我知道你喜欢她
I know you like her.
-我还知道你想让她也喜欢你  -不  别听了
- And I know you want her to like you, too. - No! Don't listen!
所以你不敢告诉她实话  但你是想说的
That's why you can't tell her the truth, but you want to!
你想告诉她
You want to tell her!
-不  -放开他
- No! - Get off him!
-告诉她  史蒂文  -我
- Tell her, Steven! - I...
告诉她
Tell her!
我喜欢这本书的结局
I liked the ending of the book!
-什么  -我  我觉得
- What? - I-I-I thought it was
丽莎和阿基米克勒斯终成眷属很甜蜜
sweet that Lisa and Archimicarus got together in the end.
他们自始自终都为对方着想
They were always so thoughtful towards each other
而且他们找到化为人形的咒语时
and I was so happy when they found the spell
我特别开心  每一页描写蛋糕的部分
to make him human, and I loved every page
我都很爱读  甚至想画一张蛋糕的画
about the cake! I wanted to draw a picture of it!
我很抱歉我装作不喜欢
I'm ... I'm sorry I pretended not to like it.
我只是  只是不想
I just ... I just didn't want
让你看不起我  -这就好多了
- you to think less of me. - Ahh. That's better.
你  你觉得
Do ... Do you think
喜欢那个结局的我是个差劲的人吗
I'm a bad person for liking the ending?
当然不是  史蒂文  那只是一本书
Of course not. I ... Steven, it's just a book.
但你真的很在乎那本书
But you really care about it.
-我更在意你啊  -即使我喜欢那场婚礼
- I care about you more. - Even though I liked the wedding?
你当然喜欢婚礼  你是史蒂文啊
Oh, of course you liked the wedding. You're Steven.
你喜欢煽情的桥段
You love schmaltz.
你说得很对
You make a good point,
但你还记得阿基米克勒斯
but don't you remember how Archimicarus
在第三卷里哭了吗  -我还以为那是因为
- cried in book 3? - I thought that was because
他们把剑丢了  -不是
- they lost the sword. - No!
是因为她差点掉进火山口
She almost fell into the volcano!
-他在为她担心  -可她会用冰冻咒语啊
- He was worried about her. - But she had access to frost spells.
确实  但阿基米克勒斯并不知情
Yeah, but Archimicarus didn't know that.
-即使是鸟也能坠入爱河  -我想你这么理解也没错
- Even birds can fall in love. - I guess you could read it that way.